cato-at-liberty.org 2019-11-09

# Cato Institute Online Privacy Policy | Cato Institute

Last updated: July 2, 2019  

The Cato Institute (“Cato”) respects the personal information privacy of users of our online websites.  We understand the need for secure handling and storage of such information.

This privacy policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit our online resources, and our practices for collecting, using, protecting and disclosing that information.

We may include on our websites features or links that allow you to interact with or connect to websites or other online resources of third parties (such as sharing through Facebook). This privacy policy applies only to Cato’s websites and online resources; it does not describe or govern the practices of any third parties.  If you choose to provide information to any third parties, including those to whom we may refer on our websites, you should refer to the privacy policies of those third parties to understand how they collect, use, and disclose the information you provide.

**Information Collection**

In using our online resources, you may voluntarily provide personally identifiable information or “PII” that identifies you as an individual, including your name and contact information.  For example, if you wish to register for an event, subscribe to a publication, or make a donation, we will need certain PII to fulfill your request.

We also collect information about your use of our Website through technological tools that we and our partners may use to collect data automatically from website users. The technologies that we use may include, for example:

  * Log Files, which may collect information such as Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, geographic location, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data.
  * Persistent and session cookies.
  * Flash cookies (or local stored objects), which are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies.

To learn more about cookies, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Your browser may offer tools to reject or delete cookies. If you reject cookies on your browser, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited. Even if you set your browser to reject cookies, we may continue to collect data automatically through other technologies.  By using any of the Sites, you are deemed to unambiguously agree to its use of any cookies that you do not disable.

Cato may use service providers, such as Google Analytics, that may use cookies to collect information about your online activities across this and other sites over time for non-advertising purposes. To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and processes data and the choices Google may offer to control these activities, please visit <http://www/google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/>.

**Uses of Your Information**

We may use the PII that you provide to us for our operational purposes, including the activities such as e-mailing you with relevant information or providing you with targeted offers.  For example, we may use your PII to:

  1. Respond to your inquiries, such as those you may submit through our “Contact Us” page or send to us by email.
  2. Process your requests, such as to subscribe to a publication or make a donation.
  3. Send You Information.  We may use your contact information to send you various types of information, including information on your activities, updates, new services, and other related items of potential interest.  As further described below, you may unsubscribe to our commercial emails by using the “unsubscribe” function in any of those emails.
  4. Improving Our Service and Outreach.  We may use PII about you, such as your feedback and comments, to make our communications with you more relevant, including by requesting further feedback, and for related internal purposes such as data analysis, audits, identifying usage trends, and enhancing our services.

We use the automatically-collected data we obtain through technological tools for our operational purposes, such as to administer and improve the site. We also use these technologies to personalize your experience with Cato and to provide functions such as recording other preferences.

**Disclosure of Your Personal Information**

We do not sell or otherwise share the PII we collect with third parties for their own marketing purposes.

With the exception of PII relating to donors, we may disclose the PII that we collect online as follows:

  1. To contractors, agents, or service providers that we use to support our business and provide our services, in which case we make reasonable efforts to ensure that they are bound by contractual obligations to keep PII confidential and use or share it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them.
  2. As part of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of Cato’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which PII held by Cato about users of our websites or other online resources is among the assets transferred.
  3. To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it; for example, if you give us an email address to use the “email a friend” feature of our website, we will transmit the contents of that email and your email address to the recipient(s).
  4. For legal purposes; including as required by law or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, property, or safety of Cato, our customers or others; and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on the Cato Institute.
  5. For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information or with your consent.

**Sponsors**

We do not sell any Sponsor information to other organizations. However, we may provide some personal information to certain “cooperative databases” as explained below.

We periodically publish the names of Sponsors on our website and in other communications. If you do not wish to have your name published, please contact us at the email address or phone number listed below.

We may use your personal information to contact you about donations or matters concerning the Institute. You may also receive periodic communications from us about news, events, opportunities to give, or other matters by mail, phone, or email. If you prefer not to receive such communications, you may notify us at the contact information provided below to opt out at any time.

To facilitate our fundraising activities, we participate in certain “cooperative databases” as do many other reputable charitable organizations. This means that we occasionally contribute certain Sponsor names and postal addresses to a shared database that may be accessed by other participating organizations who also contribute certain information to the database. Note that the cooperative database does not allow participating organizations to identify Sponsors to the Institute or access donation amounts, but may identify a Sponsor as being interested in a particular type of charitable organization (e.g. health policy). Our partner organizations will not have continued access to your name and address unless you choose to respond to their mailings. They may also be required to comply with certain laws or guidelines concerning your information, such as the Direct Marketing Association’s guidelines for ethical business practice. We do not sell your information or share your email address with cooperative databases. If you do not wish to have your information shared with a cooperative database, please contact us at the email address or phone number listed below. We strive to promptly honor all requests concerning your preferences on how we share or use your personal information.

_Sponsors may instruct that we exclude their information from any lists that we share. All such requests — directed to the Cato Institute, 1000 Massachusetts Ave. NW, Washington, DC 20001,[sponsors@cato.org](mailto:sponsors@cato.org) — will be promptly implemented._

**Children Under the Age of 13**

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect PII from children under 13. If we discover that we have received PII from a child under 13, we will delete that information.

**Choice/Opt-out**

Newsletters and Promotional Communications: We provide you the opportunity to opt out of receiving newsletters and promotional email communications from us. If you no longer wish to receive electronic newsletters and/or promotional communications, you may opt out of receiving these communications by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication.  Additionally, at any time, you may e-mail [privacy@cato.org](mailto:privacy@cato.org) to request removal of your information from our system.

**Aggregate Information**

At times, we share aggregated demographic information about our user base with selected third-party partners. We may also share de-identified information in our discretion. This aggregated or de-identified information does not identify individual users.

**Correcting or Updating Personal Information**

You may ask us to correct, update or delete your PII within our communications systems by emailing us at [privacy@cato.org](mailto:privacy@cato.org).

**Security**

Cato uses commercially reasonable safeguards to help protect the security of the PII you provide to us. For example, we may encrypt information using technologies such as Secure Sockets Layer technology (SSL).  Please note, however, that no data security protections are ever guaranteed to be 100% secure.

International Transfers of Information.  The Cato website and other online resources are intended for users in the United States.  By using any Cato online resource, you are deemed to understand and unambiguously consent to the collection and processing of your PII in the United States, with the awareness that the laws of the United States may not provide as much protection for PII as the laws of certain other countries or territories.

Updates to This Policy.  We may periodically modify this privacy policy, and if we do, the revised policy will be posted on our website, replacing the prior version.  Unless the new version materially changes the manner in which we collect, use or disclose your PII, we will post the new version without further notice to you. If we make a material change, we will post a note on the home page of [www.cato.org](http://www.cato.org/) to alert you that there has been such a change. The date the privacy policy was last revised, as identified at the top of the policy, will be the effective date of the revisions that version contains.  You may wish to periodically review the policy to ensure you understand and agree with its terms.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy or our information practices, please contact us at:  
Cato Institute  
1000 Massachusetts, Ave, NW  
Washington, DC 20001  
Attn: Chief Digital Officer
